http://www.xat.com/privacy

Privacy Policy
Your use of the service is subject our Privacy Policy.
This policy applies only to information gathered through the Service, including the download and use of Materials through the Service, but not to other offline transactions with xat, nor to transactions with any third party not owned or controlled by xat. By using the Service you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this Privacy Policy.
Data Collection
Data is collected when you use the service (e.g. create an account, make a purchase, send messages, create a ticket or send xat an email). The following data may be collected:
Accounts (including payment details but not financial data)
xat group information
Preferences
Messages sent on the service
Log files of interactions with the service and servers (including IP addresses)
Tickets and E-mails
You may provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain Services and to obtain support from xat. If you do not want to provide xat with any personally identifiable information, you should not use the Services that require such information. Other Users may also provide xat with your personally identifiable information.
xat does not collect or have access to your financial data (e.g. bank account or payment card details). If you make a purchase on the service, this will be handled by an external payment provider and you should refer to their privacy policy for any transaction you are party to.
Data Use
xat only uses this data, which may include potentially personal data, when it is lawful for xat to do so (e.g. to provide the service you have requested, for our legitimate interests in managing and improving the service and to comply with legal or regulatory obligations). Any potentially personal data that is collected is only used for the purposes for which it was originally collected.
To deliver you the Service and send you notices related to the Service, your Account and necessary updates. This includes fulfilling your requests for products and services and delivering content to you that is sent by other Users. To deliver your content to other Users (we will share your User name with Users to whom you send content). If you do not want to share this information, you should limit the content that you share and the Users that you share it with.
To manage your Account and Account access, provide you with Software and Materials, purchase confirmations, support and customer service and to keep track of support and customer service requests.
To determine the technical capabilities of your device and the appropriate content to deliver to you. xat may disclose personally identifiable information to its partners in order to provide the Service, resolve service problems and correct errors in the Service (including customer inquiries, billing and credit corrections), to communicate with you about the Service, and to enhance your experience on the Service.
Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if xat files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of xat. xat may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request, or to otherwise establish or exercise our rights, or defend against legal claims. xat may also provide such personally identifiable information order to investigate, prevent and take action regarding fraud or misuse of the Service, to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our Privacy Policy and end user agreements, and to protect the rights, property and safety of the Service, Users and others.
In addition to other Users that you designate, xat, its partners, and each of their contractors and employees may view the content that you upload to the Service in order to provide the Service and otherwise perform the tasks set forth in this Privacy Policy.
If any data is transferred to a third party for this will only be done in accordance with the privacy policy and terms of service. It will be used for the purposes related to the service and not for their own interests and only if xat is confident that it will be retained and processed in accordance with the law. xat does not rent or sell personally identifiable information, such as your name or e-mail address, to third parties including advertisers.
Your data may be transferred to a different legal jurisdiction and this will only be done where adequate level of data protection is available. For example, in the case of the USA; an approved contract and Privacy Shield registration.
Data Retention
Potentially personal data is only retained for as long as necessary. The duration the data is retained varies; considering the quantity of data, the type of data, the risk of harm should the data be accessed without authorization. In addition, there are regulatory, security, tax, law enforcement and legal requirements that may require data to be retained for a longer period of time. Where it is practical the retained data is encrypted and/or anonymized.
In some circumstances, you may request your potentially personal data and/or its deletion e.g. where there is no good reason for xat to retain or process it. The will likely require xat to confirm your identity to ensure that data is neither made available to an unauthorized third party or incorrectly deleted. Alternatively, you can use the self service tools to delete your account or group.
Cookies
When you visit any web site, it may store or retrieve information on your browser. This information might be about you, your preferences or your device and is mostly used to make the site work as you expect it to. This service stores data (e.g. HTTP Cookies, HTML5 Local Storage) in your browser to deliver the service.
Strictly Necessary
These are needed for the service to function and cannot be switched off in our systems (e.g. setting your privacy preferences, Cloudflare security functionality). You can set your browser to block or alert you about these, but some parts of the site cannot work work without them. They do not store any personally identifiable information.
Third party: Cloudflare, Amazon AWS ELB
Functionality
They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services e.g. creating an account, setting your preferences on the service.
Performance
These are used to monitor the service for the purposes of management and development of the service. They do not store any personally identifiable information.
Third party: Google Analytics
Children
xat does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. xat requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Service nor submit any personal information to the Service. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, xat does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If xat obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.
Security
xat takes appropriate steps to help ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, xat cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Service, and the Service and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Service do so at their own risk. xat cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.
Third Party Websites and Services
The service may contain links to third party websites/content. xat is not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Service links, or of which the Service is a part. If you provide any information to such third parties different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. xat strongly suggest you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.
Reasonable Efforts
xat will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when xat learn of any failure to comply with our Privacy Policy. xat sometimes release beta versions of our products and services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because these products and services are still in a test phase, xat may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, xat welcome User feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of our technology and business, and the security risks associated with using the Internet, xat does not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. To the extent permissible under law, xat shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this Privacy Policy.
Modifications of the Privacy Policy
xat reserves the rights to modify its Privacy Policy at any time. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. xat encourages you to frequently review the Privacy Policy for any modifications.
Contact, Corrections and Updates
If you have any questions or comments about this policy, please contact https://xat.com/Support.
Date: 25 May 2018
